A NETFLIX SERIES
This is it, Flavus.
For Rome.
Draw!
Release!
Take cover!
Draw!
Release!
Gaius.
Draw!
Release!
Stand down.
Retreat!
Odvulf, stay with us.
Stay with us, brother.
Gaius… he…
I know.
Brother.
Stay with us.
Brother, stay with us.
Stay with us!
-Let him go, Talio.
-Stay with us! Brother!
Germanicus slaughtered the savages!
Hail!
Hail Caesar!
Tell us, Proconsul. Tell us!
What happened?
We showed those savages
whose lands these really are!
Hurrah!
You want me, you'll get me.
It was Marbod who couldn't see
that Rome's promises don't last.
I knew something like this was coming.
But not how soon.
Imagine if Folkwin hadn't been here.
Dido?
Where is she?
She said to tell you
that you owe her nothing.
Nothing.
She left.
Where to?
To settle a long-outstanding debt.
For her own sake.
Anything else?
One wonders, is all this due to you
not keeping your promise to the gods?
I am keeping my promise to the gods.
The child is no longer mine.
Then I hope the gods see it that way too.
For your sake.
Reiks, swordsmen, women, Marbod's wife…
they're all dead.
The tribes won't take that lying down.
That much is certain.
We'll stay in the village for now.
You were banished, Segestes.
You have to ask her.
No father has to ask his daughter's
permission for anything.
So, what's your plan?
My plan? My plan seeped into the ground
with the blood of the tribes!
They've ruined everything!
If I'd been reik,
this would never have happened.
A good leader knows
how to use a defeat to his advantage.
Are you really capable of that, Segestes?
Or can you only moan
like an old washerwoman?
Proconsul Germanicus.
-Centurion Flavus.
-Dominus.
I see… that you have made Caesar proud!
Hooray for Germanicus!
Long live Gaius!
Now, there are many things
to be discussed.
Hail Caesar!
Never have I been more ashamed
to call you my son.
Father, but we--
With your thoughtless attack,
you've ruined the intricate illusion
of peace I've been building for months.
-We slaughtered them!
-All of them?
Then you've only motivated
them to retaliate.
Good. We're ready for them.
I should give you up to them.
Buy us some time.
-Father--
-Silence!
I preferred it when you were all talk.
You.
-I'd like to explain his plan.
-I gave you clear orders when we last met.
Didn't I?
-I tried to--
-Trying to accomplish something you can't…
That's the theme of your existence.
-That ends now.
-Dominus?
-Throw him in the pit.
-General!
And strip him of that uniform.
It's just a costume.
Dominus!
Barbarians are approaching the camp.
One's calling for you by name, Dominus.
Tiberius!
Get down here!
What? No Latin?
I spoke Latin to show you respect.
Respect that I also expected from you.
You have my respect, Marbod.
Oh yeah? Tell that to my wife!
I did not give permission for the attack.
It was Flavus' idea.
And Germanicus bought into it.
Fine.
Then bring them to me.
I can't do that.
Send them out!
Or you can forget our peace treaty.
I have no interest in discord, Marbod.
Go home, and let's renew
our peaceful partnership.
There will be no peace, Tiberius.
No peace until the heads
of Germanicus and Flavus are on pikes!
Draw!
Release!
Will he fetch his troops?
Yes. He already gave the order
on his way back.
He can't make the journey
in his condition.
That's true.
What about you?
My job is to protect our reik.
I won't leave his side.
I'll fetch them.
No. Too risky.
I'll fetch the Marcomanni.
Whoever goes will have to convince
the army to come here.
But…
Reik Ari of the Cherusci…
He isn't trusted in the east.
I'll go and fetch them, then.
Your tribe needs its reik now.
But you're not going alone.
You're leaving?
Yeah.
Where to?
Away.
Pity.
What do you want?
What do you two want?
Thusnelda's going
to fetch the Marcomanni army.
That's a four-day ride.
Three days.
If you know the way, but you don't.
-Right.
-But you do.
No. No, no, no. Forget it.
-One day can make all the difference.
-Ask… Ask someone else.
You were leaving anyway.
Yes. But I don't want
to have to come back again.
Then ride with me, show me the way,
and then move on.
One more ride,
and you'll be rid of all this.
We both know she'll head off anyway.
Whether you go with her or not.
I'm begging you.
Please.
We leave at dawn.
You should sleep.
Stay a bit longer.
What if you don't come back?
That won't happen.
Look at that.
A little boy, all alone in the woods.
So…
My nose tells me you might know something,
my barbarian boy.
And I can smell your breath, Roman.
It's horrible.
Grab him!
Quick!
Damn! Grab him!
Get that little barbarian bastard!
If I'd done what she wanted,
we wouldn't be here now.
I think
we'd have been here anyway.
When my army gets here…
then neither of us will rest
until the last Roman
has been driven out of our land.
Can you promise me that?
I promise you.
Find him!
He ran off that way!
There are archers all along this side.
That side is out.
And the other sides?
I can't see how.
We'll look more closely at the camp later,
before the troops arrive.
Ari?
Segestes.
Can we talk? In private?
What are you doing here, Segestes?
Want to know my plan?
So you can go running to Tiberius?
And tell him everything?
I've made mistakes.
Many mistakes.
I don't know any man as old as I am
who hasn't made any mistakes.
I want a fresh start.
I want to return to my village.
Here! I'm a Cheruscan.
Even if I were to agree to that,
I'd have to ask Thusnelda.
I'll talk to her when she returns.
She rode off today?
Where to?
I'd let you stay here
because you're Thusnelda's father.
Because I think fathers deserve
to reconcile with their children.
No matter what they've done.
Thank you for your compassion.
Segestes?
Just because I have compassion
doesn't mean I'm willing
to put up with just anyone.
There will be war.
And if you want to live here,
you have to earn it.
You'll be a man of this tribe and you'll
fight for the tribe like everyone else.
Ari… I'm not a warrior.
I'm a leader.
I can help you lead the tribe.
I have ideas for the future. Here.
I'm not interested.
Show us you have honor,
and fight for the Cherusci.
Pack your things. We're going.
There will be war. Ari's lost his senses.
He'll let the Romans
slaughter his people like pigs.
I don't think he's safe here.
You miserable old
cowardly good-for-nothing!
Don't you dare
speak to your husband like that again.
That's right.
You're my husband, Segestes.
I married you
because you were worth something.
There will be war, and you want to run.
Where to? Back to that hellhole?
No, Segestes! You'll go make sure
that we end up on the winning side.
You owe me that
because I've given you everything.
Everything!
Everything?
Are you really prepared
to give everything for this?
What?
You're lost?
No. It's just that I don't know exactly--
You're lost.
No, I'm not… I haven't gotten…
I can ride through this forest blind.
See that hill? Behind it is a clearing
where I killed my first boar.
It was more like a piglet.
Back there's the river. We cross it,
then we ride toward sunset,
then come the foothills. There.
Lost, huh?
Germanicus.
I can help you.
Germanicus…
Help me?
How?
Marbod has 70,000 men.
I know Marbod.
I know Arminius.
We're all like brothers,
born here and raised in Rome.
"Born here and raised in Rome"?
The focus shifts
to whatever suits you best, no?
Germanicus,
I know the way these men think.
-It's in my blood!
-Yes. Your barbarian blood.
That's exactly the problem.
Tiberius is wrong.
You brought glory to Rome.
I helped you.
Help me now.
Tiberius is not wrong.
Rome is sacrosanct.
And I would die to protect it.
You are just protecting yourself,
and you despise what you are.
And so Rome despises you.
Know who you are, Flavus.
Arminius betrayed Rome.
Your blood betrayed Rome.
You said it yourself.
What's running through your veins
is barbarian blood.
You are a barbarian.
Get me out of here.
Get me out of here!
Germanicus! Get me out of here!
Germanicus!
Assuming we get
to the clearing's edge unnoticed…
Of course we will.
Assuming it works,
we'd have to run across the open field,
and the archers would
shoot us all down immediately.
And then
we'd have to get over the palisades.
That's the way.
We go in as soldiers.
We'll pretend we're a unit.
We need armor, uniforms, maybe a standard.
And then?
We open the gates from the inside.
Let's go collect a few uniforms first.
No, thanks.
At least that hasn't changed.
What?
You act like nothing's wrong.
Yes, I understand you have to be strong
for your… tribe, but…
when it's just the two of us?
In the forest?
What do you want?
Ari… is… is right.
The Marcomanni will follow you.
Everyone will follow you.
But not for the reasons Ari listed.
They'll follow you because…
you don't begin to eat
until everyone else is full.
Is that what I do?
This is about Ari.
No.
This is about…
understanding, after all these years,
why you are the way you are.
What's this?
That's dirt.
No.
This… is us.
Our ancestors.
For me, it's about what was once here.
And what's here today.
And what'll be here in a thousand summers
if we can drive the Romans out.
Us, Folkwin.
All of us.
You really believe in
something bigger, huh?
Is that why you chose Ari?
Folkwin…
No matter where you are,
whether you hide away
in the furthest mountains, or…
walk to the other end of the world…
you'll always be the one closest to me.
The one who knows me best.
Who I don't need to hide anything from.
And can't hide anything from either.
Do you love him?
No luck today.
Where'd you say you were from?
Carthage.
Ready to die?
Stop! Calm down.
Calm down.
Go! Go away!
You can't kill him.
He murdered my father!
We need him.
Forget it.
Quiet!
-No! Wait!
-You?
I'll cut you open, you Roman rat.
Folkwin, he's Ari's son.
He's Ari's only son.
Please.
What are you doing here?
I…
I need to show you something.
You need to show us what?
Come on. Quickly!
Why should we trust you?
Tell us.
Otherwise, we're all going to die.
You filthy barbarians need to let me go.
And beg for mercy.
And why is that?
Come on!
Because more troops are headed our way.
More troops than you can count.
And they're going to wipe you off the map.
Bullshit.
We have scouts watching every road.
They're not coming on the roads.
We're doomed.