A NETFLIX SERIES
Hundreds of boats.
As far as the eye can see.
Only a day's ride away.
It's a whole legion. At least 10,000 men.
What about your troops, Marbod?
We can't wait that long
if they're that close.
So we must attack the ships immediately.
How do you propose we do that?
Can you even swim?
Have you ever seen such a ship?
What about Germanicus?
Tiberius won't do any bargaining.
And he won't keep his word.
We have to attack the camp
before the ships arrive.
I like it. Rob the bird of its nest.
Tiberius summoned the troops
as reinforcements.
If the camp they use
to deploy against us is gone…
They will turn around.
But how, Ari, how?
You said yourself we are too few.
Palisades, archers…
Even getting inside is a hopeless task.
And even if we succeed,
we'll still be outnumbered.
We're worth three Romans each.
I admire your courage, Thusnelda.
You're a great warrior,
and you want to fight--
I don't want to fight.
I didn't want this war.
None of us wanted this war, did we?
The Romans brought it to us.
I'd give anything for a genuine peace.
But there's no peace without freedom.
And that's why I'll do anything,
absolutely anything, for this freedom.
Fine words.
But there isn't enough blood here
to back them up.
Then we just have to mobilize
everyone we have.
Even the elderly.
Anyone who can hold a sword.
So you want…
to lead your entire people into battle?
If I don't, I won't have a people anymore.
It is nice to see you again.
To see you alive.
I'll fight for the Cherusci, Father.
I'll do everything I can to--
I can't lose you again.
You're a child.
You're not a warrior.
Not yet.
-Children don't belong on the battlefield.
-The Romans see no children.
No women, men…
To them, we're all barbarians.
Maybe I can't fight,
but the Romans don't know that.
They just have to believe that I can.
It could work.
It will.
Who goes there? Halt!
Don't shoot. I come alone.
I have information for the commander.
I am Segestes.
If you want to survive,
let me speak with him.
Go tell the prefect.
Like I said,
I want refuge in Rome
and enough gold for a decent life.
No man does
something like this just for gold.
That's something
only a man with a lot of gold would say.
Sir.
What have you got to say
before I have you flogged?
They know about the ships.
And Marbod will do anything
to avenge his wife.
They've taken Germanicus captive.
He's an idiot.
He was an idiot.
Unfortunately.
They are going to attack. Tomorrow.
They call you a fox.
A fox's burrow always has a second exit,
or even a third.
Even though he doesn't need it.
Twelve summers ago.
In Carthage.
He was a blacksmith.
With a kind face.
I don't remember.
Killing me won't change that.
Maybe it wasn't even me.
It was.
I remember.
Then what do you need me to say?
I need you to beg for my forgiveness.
And I need you
to lick my ass.
He has your lips, Thusnelda.
Thumelicus…
-Can I hold him?
-We have to make preparations.
Thumelicus.
Of course.
What's going on?
What's happening?!
Hey, men!
Silence, traitor!
Preparations are going well.
However, we are not informed
about how many they are.
As long as we secure the camp
for the ships to berth, we will be fine.
As you command, Dominus.
Good.
Any news about Germanicus?
Nothing. But are you sure you don't want
a squad to rescue him, Dominus?
No one goes in or out.
Not until the ships arrive.
I think you want to kill me…
but…
I also think you know
I'm more valuable alive…
than as a sacrifice to some memory.
Don't tempt me.
Dido!
Sleep well, my darling.
You'll survive tonight
because we need you.
But I promise you, by this time tomorrow,
I'll have cut off your filthy Roman cock
and fed it to the pigs.
Sleep well,
my darling.
Dido!
Don't run away again.
You did it once already.
Without a goodbye. Without a word.
I didn't want to involve anyone else.
Least of all you.
But it's not that simple.
You saved me back then
when I had no one else.
Folkwin,
we've always said
we owe each other nothing.
You have to find your own way.
Alone.
But what if…
my way leads me to you?
Tomorrow we fight.
Together.
Then we'll both be free.
Gaius…
Why isn't he on the other side?
He has the right
to choose his own fate too.
It's started! To the east gate!
To arms! Hurry!
They've gathered in the forest
on the east side.
Ten thousand barbarians. At least.
When will the ships arrive?
Tonight.
It can't be more than a few hours.
They're trying to cover their numbers.
Hide how few they really are.
Or how many they are.
Germanicus!
Quick, open the gate!
Open the gate!
It's a trap!
They're attacking from the other side.
They're on the other side!
Open the gate!
Attack again!
Open the damn gate!
Where is Tiberius?
Tiberius!
Marbod!
Marbod.
I'm sorry. For everything.
He's escaping! He's getting away again!
No, he isn't.
Folkwin. Hey.
Folkwin.
I hated you so much…
because I loved you so much.
You have to promise me something, Ari.
Anything, my friend. Anything.
You have to love Thumelicus
as if he were your son.
You have to love him like you loved me.
Promise me.
Promise me!
I promise.
Folkwin…
Father!
Father.
No one had seen you and…
Get on your horse.
Get on your horse!
A Roman soldier fights to the end!
To the death!
-For Rome!
-A soldier does!
Not the future Caesar!
He must know when a battle
is no longer worth fighting!
My men are fighting!
What kind of Caesar deserts his men?
Germania is one of many provinces.
And this camp is one of many.
One day,
you can decide
to burn down all of Germania.
So long as…
you get on your horse right now.
For Rome!
It's wrong, Father.
Folkwin?
Folkwin.
The ships are turning around!
We three were so young
when the wolf attacked.
We thought the world belonged to us.
But the wolf taught us
that death is always near.
And we promised to protect each other.
Until the end.
The world is full of men who conquer,
and those who stand in their way.
And just when you think
there's nothing more they can take,
they find a way
to draw you back into battle.
Ansgar!
What happened?
What happened here?
Ansgar?
Thumelicus…
-What about him?
-Thumelicus!
Ansgar?
People talk of glory and honor in battle.
But there is only life or death.
So much blood was shed.
Theirs and ours blend in the mud.
We bring children into this world
in the hope
that it will be better for them.
Life exists in the gaps between battles.
There, where love can grow.
I don't think we'll still live like this
in a thousand summers.
Maybe the gaps will get bigger.
But we're here in the now.
Fighting for the freedom of our people.
For the freedom of our children.
Thumelicus.
I said I would give anything
for this freedom.
Stop!
You'd better not, Thusnelda.
Thusnelda…
He'll be fine in Rome.
Drop your weapons.
I had no idea what that meant.
I've done my part.
I love betrayal.
But I hate a traitor.
But… we had an agreement.
Mother and child shouldn't be separated.
You are coming with us to Rome.
But by the gods, tomorrow we will be free.